A Guide to the Berry-Griggs-Parks family papers, 1813-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Berry-Griggs-Parks family papers, 1813-2014
The Library of Virginia
51677
4.225 cu. ft. and 9 boxes
Berry-Griggs-Parks family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marleen Berry Hansen of Columbus, Mississippi.
Biographical Information
Robert Taylor Berry was born 6 July 1812 at Berry Plain in King George County, Virginia. He attended Princeton University and was licensed a Presbyterian minister in 1838. He married Ann Frame Griggs 6 November 1838. Ann Frame Griggs was born 10 August 1817 in Charles Town, Jefferson County, Virginia. Robert and Ann Berry had 8 children. Ann Frame Griggs Taylor died 26 August 1857 in Charles Town and Robert Taylor Berry died 2 November 1877 in Winchester, Virginia. Their son Francis William Berry (1847-1918) married Susan Virginia Parks (1863-1936), daughter of Richard Stewart Parks (1842-1922) 10 December 1884 in Page County, Virginia. They had 9 children.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1813-2014 of the Berry, Griggs, Parks, and related families of Page County and Richmond, Virginia; Jefferson County, West Virginia; Limestone County, Alabama; and Atlanta, Georgia; consisting of accounts, books, diaries, emails, estate papers, greeting cards, invitations, letters, obituaries, photographs, poems, portraits, postcards, receipts, speeches, telegrams, wills, and other papers detailing family members' personal and professional lives, education, and military service, and providing a historical and cultural perspective on the localities in which they lived. The papers of the descendants of Robert Taylor Berry (1812-1877) and Francis William Berry (1847-1918) make up the greatest portion of the collection.
Contents List
- Lawrence Washington Berry and Katherine Rose Hodge Berry portraits (originals of portraits are located in oversize box 8). (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Robert Taylor Berry correspondence, 1854-1872. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Robert Taylor Berry estate receipts, photographs, and related papers, 1877, 1974-2012. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ann Frame Griggs Berry papers, 1843-1846, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lawrence Lee Griggs Berry papers, 1847-1861, undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Charles James Berry correspondence, 1862-1900 (originals). (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Charles James Berry correspondence, 1862-1900, 1978 (annotated transcriptions). (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Charles James Berry family papers. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arthur Holmes Berry family photographs, 1878 and undated. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Francis William Berry papers and clippings, 1867-2004. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Francis William Berry photographs. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sue V. Parks Berry papers, 1879-1937. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Richard Frame Berry papers, photographs, and clippings, 1910-2005. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lee Griggs Berry papers, 1905-1975, 2010. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lee Griggs Berry photographs. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lee Griggs Berry clippings, 1940-2014. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Lee Griggs Berry travel summary, 1922-1937. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- F. Virginius Berry correspondence, 1946-1972. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- F. Virginius Berry undated correspondence, photographs, and clippings, 1906-2010. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Lawrence Taylor Berry correspondence, ca. 1950-1970, 2002. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lawrence Taylor Berry clippings, program, and photographs, ca. 1950-2008. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Francis William Berry, Jr., correspondence, 1945-1968. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Francis William Berry, Jr., papers, photographs, and clippings. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Elizabeth Parks Berry correspondence, 1910, 1951, 1961-1965. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Elizabeth Parks Berry correspondence, 1966-1969. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Elizabeth Parks Berry correspondence, 1970-1974. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Elizabeth Parks Berry correspondence, 1975-1977, 2010. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Elizabeth Parks Berry papers, photographs, and clippings, 1932-1977. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau correspondence, 1947-1948, 1957-1964. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau correspondence, 1966-1970. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau correspondence, 1971-1976. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau correspondence, 1977. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau correspondence, 1978-1980, 2000-2001. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Keightley Berry Girardeau clippings, photographs, and papers, 1918-1975, undated. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Libby (Elizabeth Parks Berry) and Keightley (Keightley Berry Girardeau)--Sisters' travel itineraries, 1952-1960, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Jean Berry Gary papers, 1940, 1975-1985. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- C. H. Girardeau, III, papers, 1943-2009. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- C. H. Girardeau, III, clippings and photographs, 1941-1996. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Susan Berry Ware papers, 1948-2012. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Susan Berry Ware clippings and photographs, 1948-2012. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Richard Anderson Berry papers, 1951-1999. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Richard Anderson Berry papers, 2000-2014. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Richard Anderson Berry papers, undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Richard Anderson Berry clippings and photographs, 1946-2009. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Lawrence Taylor Berry, Jr., papers, 1957-2008. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Richard Parks Berry papers, 1948-1970. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Richard Parks Berry papers, 1974-2008, undated. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Richard Parks Berry photographs, 1939-2001. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Berry family photographs, 1906-1983, undated. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Berry-Griggs-Parks family genealogical notes. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Berry family genealogical notes. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Keightey family (Ireland). (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Eliza Maria Frame letter, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Jane Frame business license, 1816. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Griggs family papers, 1846-2008. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Thomas Griggs will and transcript, 1 June 1838 (dated) 18 March 1839 (proved). (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Dr. Lee Griggs and family papers. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Eliza Maria Frame Griggs to daughter Ann Frame Griggs Berry, ca. 1851. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- James Lee Griggs papers, 1860-1885. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- James Lee Griggs Timberlake letters, 1874, 1880-1882, undated. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Eliza Lee Griggs Timberlake papers, 1841-1873. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Eliza Lee Griggs Timberlake papers, 1874-1875. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Eliza Lee Griggs Timberlake papers, 1877-1885, 1896, 1951. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Eliza Lee Griggs Timberlake papers, undated. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Keightley Lee Timberlake Wilson papers, 1892-1898, 1937-1952. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Benjamin Franklin Grayson papers, 1983-2014 (referring back to 1882-1889). (Box 5, Folder 7)
- David C. Grayson papers, 1886-2006, undated (captain, CSA). (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Grayson family photographs. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Richard Stewart Parks genealogy, 1890-2003. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Richard Stewart Parks clippings, including speeches and obituary, 1901-1929, undated. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Richard Stewart Parks speech at Newmarket Battlefield, 20 May 1897. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Richard Stewart Parks photographs (including home). (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Richard Stewart Parks clippings, ca. 1982-ca. 2008 (referring back to ca. 1882-ca. 1918). (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Parks family photographs. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Emma Parks Morris obituaries, will, photographs. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Emma Parks Morris papers. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Josie Stewart Millan papers and photographs, 1939-2002, undated. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Mary Lou Warren Smoot papers, 1971-2003, undated. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Mary Ann Packett copy book, 1838-1865. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Holy Bible, published 1829 (Bible of Ann Frame Griggs Berry). (Box 7)
- The Holy Bible Containing the Old and New Testaments, published 1834 (Bible of Robert Taylor Berry). (Box 7)
- The New Indexed Bible, published 19090 (Bible of Susan Virginia Parks Berry). (Box 7)
- American Historical and Literary Curiosities, collected and edited by J. Jay Smith and John F. Watson, published 1847 (Robert Taylor Berry). (Box 7)
- A Compilation of the Messages and Papers of the Confederacy Including the Diplomatic Correspondence, 1861-1865 (2 volumes) edited by James D. Richardson, published 1905 (Richard Stewart Parks). (Box 7)
- The Life of General Thomas J. Jackson (Stonewall) in Easy Words for the Young by Mrs. M. I. Williamson, published 1899 (Lee Griggs Berry). (Box 7)
- The Songs and Ballads of the Southern People, 1861-1865 collected and edited by Frank Moore, published 1886 (Francis William Berry). (Box 7)
- Portraits of Lawrence Washington Berry and Katherine Rose Hodges Berry (from Box 1, Folder 1). (Box 8)
- Photograph of Robert Taylor Berry (from Box 1, Folder 3). (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Photograph of Francis William Berry, Jr. (from Box 2, Folder 4). (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Photographs--Reel Team and Kid Party (from Box 4, Folder 4). (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Obituary of Richard Stewart Parks in the Page News and Courier (from Box 5, Folder 11). (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Photograph of John Parks (from Box 5, Folder 15). (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Photograph of dinner honoring World War I soldiers, featuring Richard Stewart Parks in foreground (from Box 5, Folder 15). (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Wedding photographs of Emma Parks Morris (from Box 6, Folder 2). (Box 9, Folder 7)